《匹兹堡医护前线 第二季》
本影片由米奇爸爸
基于HBOMax官方译文制作
阿尔医生?
Dr. Al?
阿尔医生
Dr. Al.
后门有外伤病人
Trauma's at the back door.
等她其余的化验结果出来了通知我
Let me know when the rest of her labs are back.
那个女友并没有多大帮助
The girlfriend hasn't been much help.
她不配合吗? 不是的
Is she being uncooperative? No, not really.
显然 她跟那个小女孩凯莉的父亲
Apparently, she's only been going out with the little girl Kylie's father
只约会了几个月
for a few months.
早上8点
他现在在哪? 他在纽卡斯尔出差
Where is he now? He's in New Castle for work.
我给他留言了 让他来医院
I left him a message to come in.
好吧 等他到了来找我
Okay, come find me when he gets here.
你这周跟心理创伤咨询师聊过了吗?
You talk to the trauma counselor this week?
我正打算去
I'm going to.
我保证 很好
Promise. Okay, good.
救护车刚到 我马上过去
Medics are rolling in. I'll be right there.
从楼梯摔下来的小女孩怎么样了?
How's our little girl who took a stair tumble?
我要给她做个超声 看是否有内出血
I'm going to check for internal hemorrhage with an ultrasound.
你的直觉呢?
What is your gut telling you?
她的直觉? 对
Her gut? Yeah.
这是人工智能永远不会有的东西
It's this thing that AI will never have.
我现在不想去思考我的直觉
I don't want to think about what my gut is saying right now.
有后续情况记得来找我 找我们 如果你不介意的话
Come find me when you know more. Us, if you don't mind.
我不介意 有后续情况来找我们
I don't mind. Us, come find us when you know more.
这台外科手术你要上吗? 我实在抽不开身
Do you want to jump on this trauma? I've got my hands full.
我必须查清楚这件事
I don't want this one getting away from me.
我们还没了解全貌呢 别急着下结论
We don't know what this is yet. Don't go jumping to conclusions.
我没有下任何结论 我只是为了我的病人着想
I'm not jumping to anything. I'm just looking out for my patient.
关于桑托斯 有什么我该知道的吗?
Something I should know about Santos?
非常自信 不害怕趟浑水
Very confident, not afraid to get her hands dirty,
坚定维护患者的权益 无所畏惧
strong patient advocate, fearless.
你刚才好像在暗示她妄下结论
Seems like you were suggesting she jumps to conclusions.
不 我只是建议或者说提醒她 别那么做 什么事?
No, no, no, no. I was merely suggesting or reminding her not to. Yeah.
58岁男性 跌倒致舟骨骨折
58-year-old guy. Tripped with a scaphoid fracture.
鼻出血 神经系统检查 无局灶性体征
Epistaxis, non-focal neuro,
但否认有撞到头部
but denies head trauma.
但每次我给他检查 他的情绪状态都在恶化
But every time I check on him, his affect has drastically changed.
我的直觉告诉我有哪里不对劲
My gut is telling me something's not right.
怎么了? 没什么
What? Nothing.
你有什么计划
Your play.
先做个头部CT 如果正常的话 再做腰椎穿刺 排除脑炎
Start with a head CT. If normal, LP, rule out encephalitis.
就这么办吧
Put in your orders.
他以前来过吗? 没有
Has he been here before? No.
你联系过家属
Have you called the family
排除心理疾病史了吗? 没有 但我会的
to rule out any psychiatric history? No, but I will.
与此同时 你要参与这个外伤病例吗?
Do you want to jump on this trauma in the meantime?
是什么情况? 是个惊喜
What is it? It's a surprise.
好极了
Wonderful.
梅尔 你要来吗? 什么情况?
Mel, you want to jump on this? What is it?
是个惊喜
It's a surprise.
给我们介绍一下情况 安博伊
What do you got for us, Amboy?
艾伦·比林斯 一托盘屋顶瓦片 从两米高处坠落
Allen Billings. Pallet of roofing tiles fell eight feet,
击中其上臂 造成开放式脱位
hit his upper arm with an open dislocation.
好痛
Ouch.
两轮芬太尼 第一轮每公斤1微克 第二轮每公斤0.5微克
Two rounds of fent, 1 then 0.5 per kilo.
意识清醒 定向良好 生命体征良好
A and O, with good vitals.
梅尔 扶稳他的胳膊 好的
Mel, hold the arm steady. Sure.
比林斯先生 我是麦凯医生
Mr. Billings, I'm Dr. McKay.
我是外科的加西亚医生
And I'm Dr. Garcia from surgery.
这位是金医生 嗨
And this is Dr. King. Hi.
真的好痛
Oh, it really hurts.
给我们一分钟 我们会处理你的伤口 好吗?
Give us a minute. And we're gonna take care of that, okay?
有头痛 胸痛或腹痛吗? 没有 只有胳膊
Any headache, chest or belly pain? No, just the arm.
血氧饱和度99 脉搏104 高压116 低压78
Sats 99. Pulse 104. BP 116/78.
你怎么看 金医生?
What do you think, Dr. King?
这是开放性脱位
Oh, it is an open dislocation.
能再具体一点吗?
Can you be more specific?
我觉得是骨头向下脱出关节
I think it's inferior, yeah?
你记得专业术语叫什么吗?
Do you remember the name for that?
听上去很像《哈利·波特》里的咒语
Sounds like a Harry Potter spell.
直举性脱位
I... Luxatio erecta.
正确 检查神经血管循环状况
Correct. Check the neuro-circ.
先生 你能感觉到我的触碰吗?
Sir, can you feel me touching you?
好的 你可以动一下手指吗? 可以
Okay. Can you wiggle your fingers? Yeah.
桡动脉搏动良好 床旁超声检查阴性
Good radial pulse. E-FAST is negative.
好的 接下来做什么 麦凯医生?
Okay, what's next, Dr. McKay?
注射头孢唑林与庆大霉素 镇静后进行牵引和反牵引复位
Ancef and gentamicin. Sedate for traction, countertraction.
他需要做个CT血管造影 排除血管损伤
And he needs a CT angiogram to rule out vascular injury.
听上去很合理
That sounds like a plan.
但因为有关节开放性损伤 他需要去手术室由骨科医生灌洗清创
But with an open joint, he needs a washout in the OR with ortho.
同意 而不是在这里浪费时间
Agreed. Instead of wasting time down here,
在全身麻醉下复位应该会更容易 风险也更低
it should be easier to reduce under general anesthesia with fewer risks.
有可能
Possibly.
我们问一下骨科的意见吧
Let's get an opinion from ortho.
一看你就是新来的 医生 想法太乐观了
You're definitely new, Doctor. Wishful thinking.
骨科不喜欢管闲事
Ortho like to take their sweet time.
好了 给他镇静吧 麦凯医生
Okay, sedation orders, Dr. McKay.
100毫克丙泊酚 滴注至起效
100 of propofol. Titrate to effect.
我去备药
Be back with that.
让一下
Excuse me.
今天过得怎么样 医生?
How's your day going, Doc?
挺好的
Yeah, pretty good.
看来你的白蛋白已经输上了
Looks like your albumin's infusing.
医学生奥吉尔维和乔伊
Oh, medical students Ogilvie and Kwon are gonna be working with me.
会来协助我 你好
Hello. Student doctors.
我们是实习医生 你想让他们试试吗?
You want them to try it?
他们早晚都得上手
They got to learn sometime.
他们第一次还是观摩比较好
It's best if they watch the first one.
我可以做术前消毒和铺单 好的
I can prep and drape. Yeah.
在你的白蛋白输完之后 没错
After your albumin's in. That's correct.
为预防低血压
To prevent hypotension,
如果我们预计失血量超过五升 会给予白蛋白
we introduce albumin if we anticipate more than five liters.
上一次是六升
Last time it was six.
那相当于是一加仑半
That's, like, a gallon and a half.
高标号优质汽油
Of high-octane premium.
好的 你还需要什么吗 路易先生?
Okay, you need anything else, Mr. Louie?
不用了 女士 好的
No, ma'am. Okay.
你准备好了叫我 好的
Grab me when you're ready? Yeah.
维塔克 你今早那个放弃抢救的病人 家属在中央区8号
Whitaker, wife of your DNR this morning is in Central 8.
她知道她丈夫死了吗?
Does she know her husband died?
等你告诉她就知道了
Not till you tell her.
我马上过去
I'll be right there.
好的 务必要先找到积液区 再确认进针点
Yeah, always make sure your entry point is safe by identifying the pocket of fluid.
这样才能保证安全
That's not a pocket.
这哪是积液区 这简直是个湖
That's a lake.
是的 但你不想进针时 扎到静脉或动脉
Yeah, but you do not want to hit a vein or artery on the way in,
所以一定要用彩色多普勒确认下
so make sure you check with color Doppler.
乔伊?
Joy?
我看不到了 我什么都看不到
I can't see. I can't see anything.
因为你的眼睛是闭着的 我睁不开
That's 'cause your eye is shut. I can't open it.
我贴假睫毛的时候被胶水粘住了
It's glued shut. I was trying to put on lashes.
我的天啊 我会瞎吗?
Oh, my God. Oh, my God, am I gonna go blind?
不会 我相信我们能解决这个问题
No, no, I'm pretty sure this is something we can fix.
深吸一口气
Just take a deep breath.
好的
Okay.
你用什么把眼皮粘住了?
Okay, so you glued your eye shut with what exactly?
超级胶水
Super glue.
好吧 你平时贴假睫毛 都是用这个胶水吗?
Okay. Well, is it something you typically use to apply your lashes?
不是 这东西通常是用来
No, it's typically something you use
粘你摔碎的东西 比如咖啡杯之类的
to glue shit you break, like coffee mugs and stuff.
你知道我在说什么 那是超级胶水
You know what I'm talking about. It's super glue.
好的 明白了
Okay, okay. Yeah, got it.
你能叫J医生来吗?她知道怎么办
Can I just talk to Dr. J? She'll know what to do.
她是眼科医生吗?
Is that an ophthalmologist?
不是 她在急诊工作
No, she works here in the ER.
好吧 恐怕不行
Yeah, I don't think so,
但我知道自己在做什么
but I know what I'm doing...
大部分时候是
most of the time.
进行Z形注射时
For a Z-track, we pull up the skin
我们在进针至腹膜腔前 会先将皮肤提起
before advancing into the peritoneal space.
看上去没问题
Looks good.
液体是清亮的
Fluid's clear.
真有看上去那么疼吗?
Does that hurt as much as it looks?
也没那么糟啦
Oh, it's not too bad.
奥吉尔维 帮我插上瓶子 好的
Ogilvie, spike the bottle for me. Okay.
我们要用这些液体做什么化验?
What tests do we want on these fluids?
腹水细胞计数 排除自发性细菌性腹膜炎
Cell count to rule out spontaneous bacterial peritonitis.
答对了!确诊标准是什么 乔伊?
Ding. What would make that diagnosis, Joy?
腹水中性粒细胞绝对值超过250
Absolute neutrophil count over 250.
这边情况如何?
How are we doing in here?
他们做得很好
They are doing great.
我想他们没问题
I think they got this.
嘿 达娜 你能叫琪拉雅下来吗?
Hey, Dana, can you get Kiara down here for me?
她没接电话 她今天请假了 替她班的是...
She isn't answering her Spectralink. She's not working today. It's...
我忘了 我会查一下 然后让他们下来
I forget. I'll find out and get 'em down here.
你还需要别的什么吗? 一杯双份意式浓缩马提尼怎么样?
What else you need? How about a double espresso martini?
我欣赏你的心态
I like the way you think.
嘿 特鲁迪 我是达娜 你那边还好吗?
Hey, Trudy, it's Dana. What's going on up there?
你怎么样 宕机女孩?
What's up, Crash?
你是说除了被我妈逼疯之外吗?
You mean besides my mother driving me insane?
你就跟她说 她的努力 如果用在我这样的人身上
Just tell her that her efforts would be better suited endorsing someone like myself.
会得到更大的回报
如果你真的在考虑 完成两个住院医师项目
If you're seriously thinking of a double residency,
我劝你打消这个念头吧 你做不到
let me save you the trouble-you can't do it.
为什么?因为你做不到吗?
Why? Just because you couldn't do it?
老实说 没错
Honestly, yes.
因为你是个天才
Because you're a genius.
是的
Yes.
841的平方根是多少?
What's the square root of 841?
我不是人形计算器
I'm not a human calculator.
社工迪伦·伊森这周末替琪拉雅的班
Social worker Dylan Easton is covering for Kiara this weekend.
他马上就到
They're on their way down.
谢谢 不客气
Thank you. Yep.
该死
Oh, shit.
我接诊了一位患结膜炎的修女
I have a nun with conjunctivitis.
她的拭子样本查出了 革兰氏阴性细胞内双球菌
Her swab is showing gram-negative intracellular diplococci.
淋病?
Gonorrhea?
来信靠耶稣吧
Come to Jesus.
肯定是实验室搞错了
Well, the lab must have made a mistake.
也许是像“圣灵感孕”一样的神迹
Maybe it's an immaculate infection.
我打给实验室主管把事情问清楚 谨言慎行 小姑娘
I'll call the lab supe, clear this up. Tread carefully, missy.
那可是一个眼睛染了淋病的修女
There's a nun with gonorrhea in her eye.
你们真的要让我错过这场好戏吗?
Seriously, you guys are gonna take this away from me?
我对你们俩很失望
I'm disappointed in you two.
29.
什么?
What?
841的平方根是29
The square root of 841.
狄格比先生怎么样了?
How we doing with Mr. Digby?
他在南区21号病房 换好病号服了
He's in a gown in South 21.
我们能把他的衣物洗了吗?
Is there someplace we can get this laundered?
这些东西会直接丢进焚烧炉
Those are going right in the incinerator.
我们会给他一套新衣服
We'll get him a whole new wardrobe.
你用过石膏锯吗?你当然没有
You ever use a cast saw before? Of course you haven't.
今天是你的幸运日 跟我来
Well, today's your lucky day. Follow me.
莫汉医生 你有时间吗?
Dr. Mohan, you got a minute?
有 你见过艾玛吗?
Yeah. Have you met Emma?
今天是她第一天上班 新毕业的注册护士
First day. New grad RN.
嗨 很高兴认识你
Hi. Nice to meet you.
艾玛要学习怎么取石膏
Emma needs to learn cast removal.
石膏戴了多久? 几个月 也许几年
How long has the cast been on? Months, maybe years.
你可能得用嘴呼吸了
Probably gonna want to breathe through your mouth.
好的 狄格比先生
All right, Mr. Digby.
莫汉医生现在来帮你取掉石膏
Dr. Mohan can cut your cast off now.
你的石膏戴了多久?
How long's the cast been on?
我不知道 但真的很痒
I don't know, but it's really getting itchy.
好的 这玩意是用来切石膏的 不是切皮肤
Okay, this cuts the cast, not the skin.
这应该能缓解瘙痒
This should relieve the itching.
把石膏撑开器拿过来
Get the cast spreader.
谢谢
Thank you.
好的
Okay.
好了
你还带了些朋友来
Oh, I see you brought some friends.
天啊 那是... 蛆虫
Oh, my God, are those-Maggots.
我需要氯乙烷喷雾把它们冻掉
I'll need ethyl chloride spray to freeze them off.
在护士学校没见过这种场面吧?
Never saw that in nursing school, am I right?
现在进行大量冲洗 梅尔
Now irrigate like hell, Mel.
好的
Okay.
好 我数到三
Okay, on my count.
一 二 三
One, two, three.
快啊 混蛋
Come on, motherfucker.
肱骨头无法复位
Humeral head is not reducing.
应该在手术室进行的 我就是手术室
Should be done in the OR. I am the OR.
好了 我们要在骨科回复呼叫前 把它怼回去
Okay, we're gonna get this back in before ortho even answers the page.
梅尔 把四根手指插到肱骨头下面
Mel, stick four fingers under that humeral head.
真的吗? 对 要插得很深
Really? Yeah, get in there really, really deep.
当你感觉到牵引后 把它抬到关节盂上方
And when you feel the traction, lift it above the glenoid.
这样做会将其转变为前脱位
That will convert this to an anterior dislocation,
应该能直接复位了
and it should pop right back in.
好的 准备好了吗?
Okay. Ready to go.
一 二 三
One, two, three.
太棒了
Okay.
无菌生理盐水敷料
Oh, very cool. Sterile saline dressing.
肩关节固定带和CT
Shoulder immobilizer and CT.
看来你们不需要我了
Okay. Guess you guys don't need me anymore.
金医生 你没事吧? 没事
You all right, Dr. King? Yeah.
你看上去似乎有事
You don't seem all right.
我的庭外质询安排在今天
Well, my deposition is today.
你想聊聊这件事吗?
Do you want to talk about it?
这是禁止的
I'm not allowed to.
不 我们不一定非得聊庭外质询
No, we don't have to talk about the deposition,
但我们可以聊聊这件事对你的影响
but we can talk about how it is affecting you.
普通急诊医生平均每七年 就会遭遇一起医疗过失诉讼
Average emergency physician catches a med-mal case every seven years.
十次有九次都是医生赢
Nine times out of ten, the doctor wins.
我自己就被起诉过四次 阿尔医生你呢?
I've been sued four times myself. Dr. Al?
我从来没有被起诉过
I've never been named in a lawsuit.
但有时...
But sometime...
格蕾丝修女
Sister Grace.
这是我的住院医生 莫汉医生
This is one of my residents, Dr. Mohan.
很高兴认识你 我也很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you. You as well.
我希望我们也能招募到 像你们两位这样敬业又有才华的女性
I wish we could recruit as dedicated and talented young women as you two.
我想那是一种使命 跟治病救人很像
I imagine it's a calling, much like medicine.
是的 非常像
Yes, very much so.
格蕾丝修女 我们在显微镜下
Sister Grace, under the microscope,
看到了一种革兰氏阴性细菌
we're seeing something called a gram-negative bacteria.
很严重吗?
Is that serious?
如果不治疗的话可能会很严重
It can be if left untreated.
但幸运的是 我们可以给你打一针抗生素
But, fortunately, we can give you a shot of antibiotics,
用一升生理盐水冲洗你的眼睛
irrigate your eye with a liter of saline,
再开瓶眼药水 让你在家里每隔几小时滴一次
and give you drops to use at home every few hours.
我是怎么感染的?
How did I get it?
你眼睛里发现的细菌形态显示是淋病
So the appearance of the bacteria in your eye suggests that it's gonorrhea.
一般来说 这是通过性传播... 我知道淋病是什么 贾瓦迪医生
Traditionally, that's a sexually-I know what gonorrhea is, Dr. Javadi.
我是修女 不是白痴
I'm a nun, not a numbskull.
我经常去一个救助站帮忙
I do a lot of work at an unhoused shelter.
你会接触到脏床单、枕套 和被污染的衣物吗?
Are you handling dirty sheets, pillowcases, soiled clothes?
是的 我每天都要花很多时间洗衣服
Yes. Part of my day is spent doing laundry,
铺床和处理旧衣服
making beds, disposing of old clothes.
你会戴手套吗?
Do you wear gloves?
如果有的话
When they're available.
好吧 我们先给你打针
Okay. Well, let's get you your shot
和冲洗眼睛吧
and set up for irrigating your eye.
我相信我们肯定能趁你住院期间 搜刮出几盒手套的
I bet we can scrounge up a couple boxes of gloves while you're here.
你必须要保护好自己
It's important to protect yourself.
我们一会儿回来
We'll be back.
我为什么在这儿?
Why am I here?
我没生病
I'm not sick.
我们今天早些时候 接诊了你的丈夫伊森
Oh, we took care of your husband, Ethan, earlier today.
伊森生病了吗?
Is Ethan sick?
他病得很重
Well, he was very ill.
我们尝试了一切办法救治他
And we did everything we could to treat him,
但他的心脏还是停止跳动了
but his heart stopped beating.
我很遗憾地通知你 他已经离世了
And I'm so sorry to say that he died.
他死了?
He died?
伊森?
Ethan?
不
No, no.
你确定吗?
Are you sure?
是的
Yes.
不 伊森没生病
No, no, no, no, no. Ethan isn't sick.
不
No!
我知道你一定很难过
I know how difficult this must be for you.
超声显示肾脏没问题 没有腹内伤
Kidneys look good on ultrasound. No intra-abdominal injury.
嘿 迪伦 罗比
Hey, Dylan. Robby.
这是那个滚下楼梯的孩子凯莉吗?
Is this the "tumble down the stairs" kid--Kylie?
是的 然后呢?
Yeah. And?
我想先跟那位女友谈谈 避开小女孩
I'd like to talk to the girlfriend first, away from the little girl.
这个可以安排
We can arrange that.
随时向我们通报情况 是的 随时通报
Okay. Keep us informed. Yes, keep us informed.
被遗弃的无名氏婴儿 更多化验结果出来了
More labs are back on our abandoned baby Jane Doe.
目前为止一起正常 但你之前似乎很担心
Everything looks normal so far, but you seemed really concerned earlier.
她仍然需要导尿取样
She still needs a cathed urine.
也不一定
Or not.
袋装尿液不可信
You can't trust a bagged urine.
同意 但我们可以避免 导管造成的损伤
Agreed, but we can avoid the trauma of a catheter.
用膀胱穿刺吗?
With a suprapubic tap?
我可能还留了几手 阿尔-哈希米医生
Oh, I may have a trick or two up my sleeve, Dr. Al-Hashimi.
嘿 普林塞斯 等等
Hey, Princess, hold up.
嗨 你感觉怎么样 威廉先生? 挺好的
Hi. How you feeling, Mr. Williams? Okay.
马上要进入那个机器 我有点紧张
A little nervous about going in the machine.
我有点幽闭恐惧症
I can get a tad claustrophobic.
我明白 但我们要送你去做CT 不是核磁共振
Yeah, well, we're sending you for a CT, not an MRI.
那类似一个敞开的甜甜圈
So it's like a open doughnut.
那太好了 我喜欢甜甜圈
Oh, good. I like doughnuts.
你来了 我还以为你把我忘了
There you are. Thought you forgot about me.
没有 我只是去看了下其他病人
Oh, no, I was just with other patients.
那么 你平时有什么娱乐活动?
So what do you do for fun?
我主要是陪我姐姐做她喜欢的事
I mainly do what my sister likes.
她喜欢去肯尼伍德乐园和动物园
She loves Kennywood and the zoo.
不 我是问你
No, what about you?
你喜欢做什么?
What do you like to do?
我以前喜欢去文艺复兴集市
I used to like the Renaissance fair.
是吗? 是的
Really? Yeah.
不觉得有点中二吗?
Isn't that kind of dorky, though,
大家都装扮成别人
where everybody dresses up like somebody they're not?
是啊 但这正是乐趣所在
Yeah, but that's the fun, you know?
你可以成为任何人物和角色
You can be anyone or anything you want.
我有一次装扮成17世纪的法国女人...
I actually had this alter ego that was a 17th-century French woman--
站住!
Stop!
你没事吧 孩子?
You okay, kid?
脑子嗡嗡的
That was a doozy.
好的 准备好了吗?
Okay, we ready?
已用无菌纱布清洁并擦干
Cleaned and dried with sterile gauze.
水是凉的吗? 刚从冰箱拿出来
Is that water cold? Right out the fridge.
好的 杰西 你抬腋下 我抬腿
Okay, Jesse, you can take the armpits. I'm gonna take the legs.
一 二 三 抬
One, two, three, up.
阿尔-哈希米医生 你负责接尿
Dr. Al-Hashimi, you're gonna be our catcher.
萨米拉 你用那块纱布 在耻骨上方区域做环形擦拭
And, Samira, you're gonna do suprapubic circles with that gauze.
凉水能刺激排尿
And the cold should stimulate voiding.
就算她尿了 也可能会被污染
Even if she pees, it's likely to be contaminated.
根据《英国医学杂志》并不会
Not according to the "British Medical Journal."
他们做过“尿尿调查”
They did the wee-search.
如果白细胞或亚硝酸盐任何一项阳性 我们就导尿
Any leuks or nitrates, and we cath.
阿尔-哈希米医生 接住
Dr. Al-Hashimi, get it.
我本想邀请你加入垒球队的
I was gonna invite you to join the softball team,
但现在我要再考虑一下了
but now I'm not so sure.
好了 看起来你已经取到了 不错的中段尿样本
There we go. Looks like you got a good midstream sample.
这是条干净的毯子 好的 什么计划?
Here's a fresh blanket. Okay. Plan.
用头孢曲松 先住两天院 直到血培养结果呈阴性
Ceftriaxone, two-day admit till blood culture is negative.
接下来呢?
Next steps?
寄养机构?
Foster care.
你妈妈一定是陷入了绝境 才会抛弃你 小家伙
Oh, yeah. Someone must have been in a bad way to walk away from you, little one.
我们需要报警吗?
We need to call the police?
尿检结果出来了告诉我
Let me know what the urine dip shows.
我们会告诉你尿检结果的
We will let you know what the urine dip shows.
你一定就是阿尔-哈希米医生吧
You must be Dr. Al-Hashimi.
而你一定就是朗登医生了
And you must be Dr. Langdon.
我听说了很多关于你的事 欢迎回来
I've heard all about you. Welcome back.
这位是? 琳达·史蒂文斯
And this is? Linda Stevens.
她心绞痛发作 休息后缓解了
One episode of substernal chest pressure resolved with rest.
12导联心电图未见 ST段抬高型心肌梗死 正前往北区4号
12-lead negative for STEMI. Heading for North 4.
你好 我是阿尔-哈希米医生
Hello, I'm Dr. Al-Hashimi.
很高兴认识你 很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you. Nice to meet you.
女士 这是一家教学医院
Ma'am, this is a teaching hospital.
可以让我们的几位实习生 跟我一起吗?
Is it okay if some of our trainees join me?
没问题
Not a problem.
维塔克医生 贾瓦迪 奥吉尔维 乔伊
Dr. Whitaker, Javadi, Ogilvie, Joy...
都过来
...gather round.
朗登医生 你也可以留下
Dr. Langdon, you are more than welcome to stay, too.
最多待一会吧 我们分诊挺忙的
Maybe for a minute. We're pretty busy in triage.
好的
Okay.
史蒂文斯女士
Ms. Stevens...
我手机里有一款应用 能记录我们的谈话
...I have an app on my phone that can listen to our conversation
和身体检查的所有细节
and the details of my physical exam
并将其输入到你的病历中
and write it all up in your medical record.
哇 太牛了
Wow.
所有信息都将受到保护并严格保密
It's protected, confidential,
甚至不会在我的手机上留存 这意味着...
doesn't even stay on my phone...
怎么了?
What's going on?
某个混蛋嫌犯一看到警察就跑了
Some A-hole perp took off when he saw the cops,
把她从凳子上撞翻在地
knocked her backwards off a stool.
天啊 头部创伤 没有失去意识
Oh, Jesus. Head trauma, no LOC.
好的 你得好好检查一下
Okay, you need to get checked out.
我没事 你没得选
I'm fine.No choice.
这是工伤
It's work-related.
给她找个病房 准备做颅骨钻孔
Let's find her a room and prep for a burr hole.
什么?
What?
我忘记你多爱开玩笑了 坏血病船长
I forgot how much you like to joke, Captain Scurvy.
坏血病船长是谁?
Who the hell's Captain Scurvy?
那是我们圈内人的梗
It's an inside thing.
肩膀脱位的病人还好吗?
How's our shoulder guy?
像婴儿一样酣睡着
Oh, he slept like a baby.
CT血管造影未见血管损伤
CT angio shows no vascular injury.
你那个滑倒摔伤 且情绪不稳定的病人呢?
What about your slip-and-fall guy with a labile affect?
迈克尔·威廉 他还在做CT
Michael Williams. He's still in the scanner.
他似乎安定下来了 不需要一刻不离地盯着了
He seems to have settled down, so he doesn't need babysitting.
很好 也许他想通了
Good. Maybe he's coming around.
骨科可以带比林斯先生做手术了
Ortho can take Mr. Billings here up for surgery.
且慢 水手 罗宾纳维奇医生
Belay that order, sailor. Dr. Robinavitch.
海斯廷斯护士 你可以叫我罗比
Nurse Hastings. You can call me Robby.
你可以叫我诺艾儿
You can call me Noelle.
你可以告诉我这是怎么回事
You could just tell me what the hell's going on here.
这是诺艾儿
This is Noelle.
她是我们的... 床位控制主管 我们见过
She's our...Bed control manager. No, we met.
病例主管 病例主管
Case manager.
这个人不能留下
And this guy won't be staying.
他需要手术
Oh, he needs surgery.
他的保险可以报销 西桥纪念医院的费用
Which his insurance will pay for at Westbridge Memorial,
但我们这里不行
not here.
等等 所以我们得转院?
Wait, so we have to transfer?
如果他情况稳定的话
If he's stable.
我觉得他算稳定了
I believe that he is.
往好的一面想 我们能空出一个床位了
Look on the bright side. We're gonna free up a bed,
让病人出院吧
discharge a patient.
对我们来说确实是好事 但对他就不是了
I mean, that's great for us, not so good for him.
他会在西桥得到很好的照料
He will get great care at Westbridge,
你同意吗 罗比?
don't you agree, Robby?
我确信他会的
I'm sure that he will. Yeah.
我错过什么了吗?
What am I missing?
艾伦·比林斯还有什么事 是我不知道的吗?
Is there something else happening with Allen Billings that I don't know about?
医疗层面没有 这只是一次简单的保险转院
Not medically. This is just a simple insurance transfer.
好吧
Yeah, okay.
她这是怎么了?
What's that about?
没什么
Nothing.
感觉不像没什么
Didn't feel like nothing.
麦凯医生有超乎寻常的共情能力
Dr. McKay has a very heightened sense of empathy.
什么意思?
Meaning?
意思是她很擅长察言观色
Meaning she's good at picking up on stuff.
你什么都没说吧? 没有
You didn't say anything, did you? Nope.
我订阅了福斯塔夫的建议
I subscribe to the Falstaff advice.
谨慎比蛮干更重要
Discretion is the better part of valor.
你还是打算今晚走吗? 是的
You still planning on leaving tonight? Yep.
我不明白你为什么不能明早走
I don't understand why you can't leave in the morning.
能失陪一下吗?
Will you excuse me for a second?
我得趁那个病人跟监护人分开时 跟她聊几句
I got to go talk to a patient while she's separatedfrom her caregiver. Oh, yeah.
这不太合适吧 是不合适
That doesn't sound ideal. It's not ideal.
但我得搞清楚事情真相 我走之前会找你的
I got to figure out what's going on. And I'll find you before I leave.
好的
Okay.
好吧 不能再这样下去了
Okay, you got to stop this.
海斯廷斯
Hastings.
伊万斯
Evans.
希望你知道自己在做什么 这话是什么意思?
Hope you know what you're doing. What is that supposed to mean?
我已经是大姑娘了
I'm a big girl.
好吧 大姑娘
Okay, big girl.
我没事
I'm fine.
那很好 跟随我的手指
That's good. Follow my finger.
头有什么感觉? 有一点酸痛
How's the head? It's a little sore.
身体前倾 让我看看
Lean forward. Let me take a look.
是啊 你会鼓起一个大包
Yeah, you're gonna have a pretty good goose egg.
头疼吗? 一点点
Headache? A little.
我可以给你拿点泰诺 除非你需要一些更强劲的东西
I can get you some Tylenol, unless you need something stronger.
不用 我对药物很敏感
Oh, no, that's okay. I'm not very drug tolerant.
你很幸运
Lucky you.
我很高兴你回来了
You know, I'm glad you're back.
谢谢 我也很高兴能回来
Thanks. Yeah, I'm glad to be back.
你知道我为什么离开吗? 你应该去看看我的病人...
You know why I was away? I should see my patient--
不知道
No, not really.
我听过一些传言
I mean, I heard rumors,
但我很早之前就明白了传言不可信
but I learned a long time ago not to listen.
我去了康复中心
I was in rehab
为了戒除对安定药物的瘾
for an addiction to benzos.
是的 但我现在已经成功戒断了
Yeah, but I'm clean now,
而且我从未因此影响我的工作
and it never affected my work.
我只是需要一劳永逸地 把它从我身体里清除干净
I just needed to get it all out of my system once and for all.
我之前没有采取正确的处理方式
Yeah, I didn't handle things the way I should have.
我以为可以治好自己 我让很多人失望了
I thought I could treat myself, and I let a lot of people down.
我很抱歉 梅尔
I'm sorry, Mel.
你没有让我失望过
You never let me down.
我有
Yeah. Yeah, I did.
我应该以身作则 而不是成为反面教材
I should be setting an example, not a cautionary tale.
嘿
Hey.
你还好吗?
How you doing?
我挺好的
I'm okay.
听着 刚才的事我真的很抱歉
Listen, I'm really sorry about all that.
那家伙昨晚抢劫了一家酒类专卖店
The guy robbed a liquor store last night.
他试图骑自行车逃离 但意外摔倒了 然后他就徒步逃跑了
He tried to get away on a bicycle but wiped out and took off on foot.
他肯定是一瘸一拐地走进了这里
He must've hobbled in here,
我想他更多是为了躲藏 而不是缝针
more so to hide out than to get stitched up, I think.
你抓到他了吗? 我们会的
You catch him? We will.
你能提供的任何线索都会有帮助
Anything you could tell us about him will help.
你觉得他会用真实身份吗?
You think he gave legit information?
可能不会 但我们也没别的办法了
Probably not, but it's all we have at the moment.
如果我们找到他
If we do find him,
你可能需要出庭作证 金医生
you may have to testify in court, Dr. King.
出庭? 作为关键证人
"In court"? As a material witness.
就是证明一下 他的伤情和治疗情况 很简单
Attest to his injuries, his treatments...simple stuff.
到时再说吧
Yeah, but we'll cross that bridge when we come to it, right?
梅尔?
Mel?
你好好休息 我马上回来
Rest here a minute. I'll be right back.
我没事 真的 我可以...
You know, I'm fine, really. I should--
就十分钟 拜托了 这是医嘱
Ten minutes, please. Doctor's orders.
急诊科是会有点刺眼和吵闹
ER can be a little bright and noisy.
足背动脉
Dorsalis pedis
和胫后动脉搏动2+ 双侧对称
and posterior tibial pulses 2 plus and equal.
检查结果一切正常 女士
Your exam is perfect, ma'am.
很高兴听到这个消息
Oh, that is good to hear.
你的血检结果出来后 我会再来看你
I will be back when your blood tests are ready.
如果胸痛复发了 立刻告诉我们
Let us know if the chest pain returns.
谢谢 不客气
Thank you. You are so welcome.
你怎么看? 我觉得不是心脏的问题
What do you think? Well, I don't think it's cardiac.
我是说 你对那个应用怎么看?
I mean, what do you think of the app?
没有看到全貌很难说
I mean, it's hard to say without seeing the full thing.
那就看看吧
Take a look.
琳达·史蒂文斯
天啊
Oh, my God.
你知道这能节省多少时间吗?
Do you know how much time this will save?
研究显示 你能节省80%的写病历时间
Studies show you can spend 80% less time charting.
你能更快离开这里
You'll get out of here sooner,
提升病人和医生的满意度
improving both patient and physician satisfaction.
不好意思 这上面说 她在服用利培酮 一种抗精神病药
Oh, excuse me. It says here she takes Risperdal, an antipsychotic.
但她失眠时服用的是替马西泮
She takes Restoril when needed for sleep.
所以这是... 人工智能
So is that... AI,
人工智障
"almost intelligent."
目前生成式人工智能的正确率有98%
Generative AI is 98% accurate at present.
你们必须仔细核查并改正微小错误
You must always carefully proofread and correct the minor errors.
它很优秀 但远不及完美
It's excellent but not perfect.
这简直太棒了
This is amazing.
你会说波斯语? 我本科在加州大学洛杉矶分校念的
You speak Farsi? Oh, I did my undergrad at UCLA.
我有很多波斯同学
A lot of my friends were Persian.
所以你学了波斯语?
So you learned the language?
学了点皮毛 足够破冰了
Enough to break the ice.
你真令我惊讶
I am impressed.
我也很惊讶...
Me too...
你竟然有朋友
that you had friends.
维塔克医生 我见过那个 有阿尔茨海默症的遗孀了
Dr. Whitaker, I said hello to your widow with Alzheimer's,
但她只想跟医生谈
but she only wants to talk to a doctor.
她早都该换纸尿裤了
She's also very overdue for a diaper change.
好的
Okay.
谢谢 奥吉尔维 你跟我来
Yeah, thank you. Ogilvie, you're with me.
走吧
Come on.
博斯蒂克太太?
Mrs. Bostick?
章鱼壶心肌病?心碎综合征? 不是
Takotsubo? Broken heart syndrome? No.
你好?
Hello?
嘿 你想见我?
Hey. You wanted to see me?
才没有
No.
你是谁?
Who are you?
我是维塔克医生 我们聊过你丈夫
I'm Dr. Whitaker. We talked about your husband?
伊森
Oh, Ethan.
能让他来看我吗?
Oh, can he please come see me?
不能
No.
很不幸 他病得很重
Unfortunately, he was very sick,
已经去世了
and he died.
伊森...死了?
Ethan? Died?
不 这不可能
No. No, that's impossible.
不
No.
你有什么爱好吗?
What do you like to do for fun?
我喜欢骑马
I love horseback riding.
你爸爸会带你去吗?
Does your dad take you? Yep.
是的 有时他也会骑 但大多数时候 他都是看着我骑
Sometimes he even rides, but most of the time, he just watches me.
你从马上摔下来过吗?
Have you ever fallen off?
你被甩下来过吗? 没有
Have you ever been thrown? Nope.
我骑术很好
I'm a very good rider.
你有自己的马吗? 要是有就好了
Do you have your own horse? I wish.
我们住在公寓里
We live in an apartment.
好的 凯莉 我们现在要抽一点血
Okay, Kylie, we need to take some blood now.
一定要抽吗?
Do you have to do that?
是的 但我保证我会动作超快 只会疼一下子 好吗?
Yeah, but I promise it'll go super fast and only hurt for, like, a moment, okay?
我现在要把这个皮筋绑在你胳膊上
So I'm just gonna put this rubber band
好让血管看得更清楚
around your arm to help me find your vein better.
然后给你消毒
And then this makes sure no germs
确保在抽血时 不会有细菌进入你的身体
get in your body when we do it.
好了 现在你会感到一点刺痛
Okay, now you're just gonna feel this teeny little prick.
但你可以把头别过去 好吗?
But you can look away, okay?
最糟糕的部分结束了
Worst part's over.
勇敢的小姑娘
Tough little girl.
是啊 小女孩可以跟小男孩一样勇敢
Yeah, well, little girls can be just as tough as little boys,
甚至更勇敢 是的
even tougher. Yes.
我只希望她不是被迫变得这么勇敢的
I just hope it's not because she's become accustomed to pain.
起码要给她做一次外阴检查
At the very least, she's gonna need a visual exam
看是否有创伤迹象
of external genitalia to look for signs of trauma.
我可以让阿尔-哈希米医生...
I can have Dr. Al-Hashimi--
不用 她是我的病人 我来就行
No, she's my patient. I can do it.
干净清澈
Nice and clear.
如果感染了 会变得浑浊
With an infection, it'd be kind of cloudy.
乔伊 我上夹子后 准备插第三个瓶子
Joy, get ready to spike the third bottle here after I clamp.
这边没问题吗? 没问题
All good in here? Yes.
维塔克医生正在解释 自发性细菌性腹膜炎
Dr. Whitaker was just explaining that with SBP,
会导致液体呈浑浊状
we would see a turbid appearance.
然而 他忽略了一点 出现血性腹水有两种可能
However, he failed to mention that bloody fluid indicates either a traumatic tap
要么我们扎到血管了
or the likelihood of hepatocellular carcinoma,
要么很可能是肝癌
in which case, we would send for cytology.
如果是后者 我们要送去做细胞学检查
That is correct.
正确
Kid knows his shit.
这孩子有认真做功课
He's so smart.
他可真是个大聪明
嘿 嘿
Oh, hey. Hey.
正式成为医生是什么感觉?
How's it feel to officially be a doctor?
说实话 感觉挺好的
It's pretty cool, actually.
我今天拿到了第一笔工资
I get my first paycheck today.
只有第一周的 但我接受了
It's only for the first week, but I will take it.
那两个医学生怎么样?
How are the med students?
乔伊挺特立独行的
Joy is pretty peculiar.
另一个 奥吉尔维
And the other guy, Ogilvie,
他很聪明 而且喜欢炫耀
is really smart and likes to show people.
他真的惹人烦
He's obnoxious.
他是你的竞争对手
Well... What he is, is your competition.
他是个野心家 得了吧
He's a gunner. Yeah, right.
他不是我的竞争对手
He's not my competition.
他是从其他州来的 要进行为期四周的实习
He's from out of state for a four-week sub-internship.
你不觉得他在瞄准
You don't think he's angling
明年急诊科住院医师的位置吗?
for an emergency residency spot here next year?
就算是...
I mean, even if he was...
怎样?
What?
他不可能跟你的天才大脑抗衡?
He couldn't possibly compete with your gigantic brain?
如果我是你 我会打起十二分精神 宕机女孩
I'd step it up if I were you, Crash.
她还这么叫你?
Oh, she's still calling you that, huh?
我已经不在乎了
I don't really even care anymore.
她不也叫你哈克贝瑞吗?
I mean, she still calls you Huckleberry.
是啊 但我们现在是朋友了 所以...
Yeah, but, you know, friends now, so...
朋友不会给彼此起烂绰号
Friends don't give each other shitty nicknames.
你觉得“哈克贝瑞”这个绰号很烂吗?
You think Huckleberry is a shitty nickname?
不 “哈克贝瑞”很可爱
No. No, Huckleberry is cute.
挺酷的 不像“宕机女孩”
It's cool. It's not like Crash.
拜托 “宕机女孩”也挺酷的
Oh, come on, man, Crash is pretty cool.
就像 你懂的 突然宕机了
It's, like, you know, Crash.
有股冲劲
It's got momentum.
贾瓦迪医生 维塔克医生
Dr. Javadi, Dr. Whitaker.
我还是实习医生 维塔克现在是真正的医生了
Oh, I'm still a student doctor. Whitaker's the real deal now.
是啊
Right.
欢迎回来 谢谢
Welcome back. Thanks.
谢谢 很高兴能回来
Yeah, thank you. It's good to be back.
好的 我被流放到“分诊岛”了
Okay, I will be in exile on Triage Island
跟其他瘾君子一起 如果有人要找我 就去那儿吧
with the rest of the drug addicts, if anyone needs me.
这太奇怪了 非常奇怪
That was weird. Very.
贾瓦迪的生日派对在哪举办?
暂时还没计划
什么?
What?
那我们就计划一下...
你觉得贾瓦迪看着像21岁吗?
现在像了 这地方催人老
姑娘 拜托
你不老
我也不老
但有些人老了
这一定很疼
That's got to hurt.
朗登医生 克林特·汉森
Dr. Langdon, Clint Hansen,
这是他表妹蒙娜
his cousin Mona.
这是怎么发生的?
How'd this happen?
被煎锅里的培根油溅到了 看着可不止是溅了点油
Bacon grease from a big griddle. Oh, looks like more than a splatter.
某个白痴在我洗碗的时候 把锅直接放进了水槽
Yeah, some fool poured it in the sink while I was washing dishes.
我离得很远
I was so far away.
你看都没看就伸手拿肥皂
You reached for the soap without even looking.
你没听到我说话吗? 没 水龙头开着听不到
You couldn't hear me? No, not with the water running.
谁会把培根油倒进下水道啊?
Who the hell pours bacon grease down the drain?
水槽下面有个罐子
There's a jar under the sink.
你可以早点告诉我 你是我的客人
Well, you could have told me that. You're a guest in my house,
现在你把我的下水道彻底堵死了
and now you've totally fucked up my plumbing.
我们还是专注于治疗烧伤吧
Okay, how about we focus on treating this burn?
我去拿麻醉药
I'll grab the LET.
我们得剪掉一些死皮
We're gonna need to trim off some of the dead skin
防止感染
so it doesn't get infected.
我是负责早午餐自助餐的 你能快点吗?
I'm in charge of the brunch buffet. Can you make it fast?
当然 好的 我们... 这个病人是坐车来的
Sure. Yeah, we-This one came in by car.
我只知道他叫奥兰多·迪亚兹
All I got is a name--Orlando Diaz.
怎么回事? 他被钢筋绊倒了
What's the story? He tripped over some rebar.
是绊倒了还是晕倒了? 不知道
Tripped or fainted? I don't know.
奥兰多 睁开眼睛
Orlando, open your eyes.
他撞到头了吗? 应该是吧
Hit his head? I guess.
你为什么不叫救护车? 他不肯 他当时还能说话
Why didn't you call 911? He wouldn't let me. He was talking--
现在不怎么说了
not so much now.
奥兰多 迪亚兹先生
Orlando. Mr. Diaz.
天哪 他喝醉了?
Jesus. He drunk?
不是 呼气有酮味 他有糖尿病吗?
No. Ketones on his breath. He diabetic?
我不知道
I don't know.
头部创伤 意识状态改变 可能并发糖尿病酮酸中毒 立即急救
Altered head trauma, possible DKA. Call it overhead.
启动一级创伤急救
Code trauma tier one now. Code trauma tier one now.
维塔克医生 你的评估一针见血
Dr. Whitaker, your assessment was spot-on.
你那位患有阿尔茨海默症的遗孀 需要安置到养老院
Your Alzheimer's widow definitely needs placement.
有今天就能接收她的养老院吗?
Do you have a nursing home that can take her today?
我也希望有
I wish.
医保规定 必须住院满三天
Medicare requires a three-day hospitalization
他们才会批准
before they'll approve that.
我没有让她住院的理由
I don't really have a reason to admit her.
但是我有
But I do.
她已经丧失了行为能力
She's gravely disabled.
我会让她坐轮椅 这个方案可行
I'll put her on a cycle. We'll make it work.
谢谢你 卡勒布
Thank you, Caleb.
你有时间吗 迈克尔?
Yeah, you have a few moments, Michael?
我没有
Actually, I do not.
但我这边处理完之后 我会去找你的
But once I get things settled here, I will come and find you.
好的
Okay.
罗比医生
Dr. Robby,
迪伦跟那个女友谈过了 罗比!
Dylan just talked to the girlfriend-Robby!
等会儿再跟我汇报吧 他怎么了?
You'll have to fill me in in a minute. What do you got?
意识状态改变 我判断不了 他是因为意识不清才摔倒的
AMS. I can't tell if he fell 'cause he was altered
还是因为摔倒了意识不清
or he's altered because he fell.
他呼气有酮味 交给我就行了 谢谢
There's ketones on his breath. Okay, I got this. Thank you.
好吧 就剩咱俩了
All right, I guess it's just us.
那个女友是怎么说的?
What did the girlfriend have to say?
吉娜对此显得很困惑和紧张
Well, Gina seems a little confused and on edge by this,
但我并不怀疑虐待跟她有关
but I'm not suspicious about abuse on her part.
那凯莉的父亲呢?
What about Kylie's father?
我是社工 不会读心
Well, I'm a social worker, not a mind reader.
我得跟他谈谈
I need to speak with him.
是啊 他这会儿应该到了的
Yeah, he's supposed to come in.
如果没来 那就是心虚
If he doesn't, looks pretty guilty.
咱们先别急着下结论
Let's not jump to any conclusions just yet.
我没有
I'm not jumping.
我只是想说 如果那家伙不出现
I'm just saying, if this dude doesn't show up,
我会亲自去找他
hell, I'll go find him myself.
开玩笑的
Kidding.
在她父亲来之前 我会先跟凯莉聊聊
I will speak to Kylie before her dad gets here.
如果他会来的话
If he shows up.
是的
Yes.
那绝对是酮味 我们需要测个快速血糖
That's definitely ketones. We need to do an Accu-Check.
我来吧 他心动过速 心率124
I'm on it. He's tachy at 124.
血氧饱和度97 高压106 低压72
Pulse ox 97. BP's 106/72.
双侧肺滑动正常 肠鸣音良好
Lung sliding bilaterally. Good bowel sounds.
腹部柔软无压痛 你怎么知道无压痛?
Abdomen is soft, non-tender. How do you know it's non-tender?
因为我没看到他呲牙咧嘴
Because I didn't see any grimacing.
他没意识了 扎静脉针他都不会皱眉头的
He's altered. He didn't even flinch for the IV start.
我是想说无僵硬
I meant to say non-rigid.
双侧脚趾向下弯曲 无证据表明上运动神经元受损
Toes down, going bilaterally, no evidence of upper motor neuron deficit.
很好 床旁超声阴性
Good. E-FAST negative.
需要我帮忙吗?
How can I assist?
你可以去看看麦凯医生 或是桑托斯医生
You can check in with Dr. McKay or Dr. Santos.
如果你不介意的话 我想旁观 了解一下你是如何工作的
If you don't mind, I'd like to observe, learn how you handle things.
血糖值很高 超过500了
Blood sugar's critical high-it's over 500.
警铃大作 听上去像是糖尿病酮症酸中毒
Ding, ding, ding, ding. Sounds like diabetic ketoacidosis.
我们必须马上治疗
We need to start treating that,
然后做CT排除颅内出血
then right to CT to rule out an intracranial bleed.
有一个严重呼吸窘迫患者 预计三分钟后到达
Severe respiratory distress coming in. ETA three minutes.
我把他们安排到创伤一室 好的
I'll stick them in Trauma 1. Yep.
你想让我接手吗? 太好了 谢谢
Would you like me to take that? Yes, please. Thank you.
他需要胰岛素滴注 对吧?
This guy needs an insulin drip, right?
每公斤体重0.1单位?
0.1 units per kilo?
不 得先查过血钾
No, not without knowing his potassium.
胰岛素会导致钾向细胞内转移
Insulin causes an intracellular shift.
如果血钾浓度低于3.5 滴注会害死他的
And if the potassium is under 3.5, the drip would kill him.
完全正确
That is very true.
我们可以从乳酸林格液开始
We can start with lactated ringers.
以每小时一升的速度输注 直到我们拿到
1 liter per hour until we get the results
生化七项和静脉血气的结果
from the chem-7 and the VBG.
他为什么会出现糖尿病酮症酸中毒?
Why is he in DKA?
也许他没注射足够的胰岛素
Maybe he's not taking enough insulin.
更常见的情况是有诱发事件
More frequently, a precipitating event can be identified,
比如肺炎、尿路感染、中风
such as pneumonia, urinary tract infection, stroke,
心肌梗死或胰腺炎
myocardial infarction, pancreatitis.
是的 我们都会查的 这是标准流程
Yeah, we always check for those.
对吧 莫汉医生?
They're part of the standard order set, right, Dr. Mohan?
他是疯癫的吉米爷爷那一支的
He's from crazy Grandpa Jimmy's side.
她是我爷爷的弟弟那一支的
She's from my grandfather's brother's side.
里奇叔祖父也是个神经病
Grandpa Ricky is still a psycho.
这显然是家族遗传 等等
Clearly runs in the family. Well, hold on.
你的祖父是里奇和吉米·汉森?
Your grandparents are Ricky and Jimmy Hansen?
那个赛车家族?
From the racing family?
很不幸 是的
Unfortunately.
有件事需要你处理一下
I got something that needs attention.
不会又是个婴儿吧
Not another baby.
抱歉 失陪一下
Sorry. Excuse me.
这是兰德尔先生
This is Mr. Randall.
他已经勃起了八个小时
He's been erect for the last eight hours.
应该早就软下来了 对吧?
Should have gone down by now, right?
这种情况时有发生 你回来是明智的选择 兰德尔先生
It happens. It's a good thing you came in, Mr. Randall.
我马上给他办理入院
I'll take him right back.
你能劝劝那对斗嘴的表亲吗?
Do you mind finishing up with the Bickersons?
还是不了吧
I'd rather not.
那么 兰德尔先生... 叫我伊恩吧
So, Mr. Randall-Ian.
伊恩 你是吃了什么东西 导致这种状况的吗?
Ian, did you take anything that might have led to this condition?
我注射了一支勃起功能障碍药剂
I used an ED injection--two, actually.
其实是两支
I gave myself a second shot,
我又给自己打了一针 一边一针
one on each side.
所以 你用了双倍的推荐剂量?
So double the recommended dosage?
那是我们的结婚纪念日
It's our wedding anniversary.
很重要吗?
Is this a big one?
我是说纪念日 很重要吗?
The anniversary, is it important?
有什么特殊意义吗? 比如 里程碑式的...
Like, significant? Like, a milestone or--
那是我们的二十年结婚纪念日
It's our 20th. Oh, nice.
真好 恭喜
Well done. Congratulations.
血糖 521 血钠 129
Glucose 521. Sodium 129.
血钾 3.7 氯 97
Potassium's 3.7. Chloride's 97.
碳酸氢盐 8 这代表什么?
Bicarb's 8. Meaning?
我们可以开始胰岛素滴注 并在每升液体中加入20单位的钾
We can start the insulin drip and add 20 of K to each liter.
阴离子间隙高达24 它应该小于10的
Big anion gap of 24. It should be under 10.
我们通过监测这个指标 来评估病情发展
We follow it to assess progress.
其实 2024国际指南中指出
Actually, the 2024 international guidelines
不应以阴离子间隙作为判断依据
state that anion gaps should not be used, as they can be misleading
因为在合并高氯性代谢性酸中毒时 它可能产生误导
in the presence of hyperchloremic metabolic acidosis.
我最近接诊了一个重症监护室病例
I recently had a case in the ICU.
静脉血气结果出来了 pH值6.97
VBG is back--pH of 6.97.
正常是7.4
Normal's 7.4.
是什么导致了酸血症?
What causes the acidemia?
没有胰岛素 身体就无法利用葡萄糖
Without insulin, the body can't use glucose,
于是它分解脂肪产生酮体
so it breaks down fat-producing ketones,
导致严重酸中毒 而这可能引发心脏骤停
leading to severe acidosis, which can cause cardiac arrest.
但高血糖会导致身体 排出更多的水分和电解质
But the hyperglycemia causes the body to excrete more water and electrolytes,
从而引起严重脱水 心脏和肾功能障碍
leading to severe dehydration, cardiac and renal dysfunction.
胰岛素滴注 含钾补液 每小时测一次指尖血糖
Insulin drip, fluids with KCL, capillary glucose every hour,
每四小时查一次生化七项
chem-7 every four hours.
重症监护室那边 会要求放一根双腔中线导管
ICU is gonna want a double lumen midline, too.
我可以 我可以
I can do it. I can do it.
6号半手套 7号半手套
6 1/2 gloves. 7 1/2 gloves.
我想说一下 我们评价学生 不仅基于他们的知识储备
Can I just say, we evaluate our students not only on their fund of knowledge
和操作技能
and on their procedural mastery
但更重要的是 我们会考察他们的团队协作能力
but, also, maybe more importantly, on their skills as team players?
他可以 她可以
He can do it. She can do it.
奥特罗 你能给大家介绍一下情况吗?
Otero, will you update everyone?
巴瑞·米歇尔 在帕梅拉餐厅吃早饭
Barry Mitchell. Eating breakfast at Pamela's.
突发呼吸窘迫
Sudden onset respiratory distress.
有喘鸣音 血氧饱和度尚可 但说话困难
Some stridor. Decent pulse ox but trouble speaking.
他们试过海姆立克急救法吗? 三次
And they tried the Heimlich? Three times.
有哮喘病史吗?
Any history of asthma?
准备插管 同意
Set up for intubation. Agreed.
好的 先生 请挪过来
Okay, sir, scoot across.
他们能自己挪到床上 就是个好兆头
Always a good sign when they slide over on their own.
他从餐厅来的 上气道梗阻
Came from a diner with an upper-airway obstruction.
海姆立克法没起效 我们得检查下
Didn't clear with abdominal thrusts. We got to take a look.
心率118 血氧饱和度96
Heart rate's 118. Pulse ox 96.
米歇尔先生 我们要给你镇静 然后看一下你喉咙里面 好吗?
Mr. Mitchell, we're gonna sedate you to look down your throat, okay?
抽取氯胺酮和罗库溴铵
Draw up ketamine and rocuronium.
只用氯胺酮怎么样?
What about ketamine only?
不行 我们需要肌肉完全松弛 来确保首次插管成功
No, we need full paralysis for a successful first-pass intubation.
如果只是个异物 可能根本不用插管
Might not need an intubation if it's just a foreign body.
我们不能做这个假设
We can't assume that.
有可能是声门下狭窄 或者会厌炎
It could be subglottic stenosis, epiglottitis.
氯胺酮和罗库溴铵都准备好了
I got ketamine and roc.
只用氯胺酮 80毫克
Ketamine only, 80 milligrams.
既然如此 就交给你这位大能人全权处理了
In that case, I'll leave this in your capable hands.
西他卡因喷雾和杨克氏吸痰管 谢谢
Cetacaine spray and a Yankauer, please.
半小时前 我告诉过你我从没被投诉过
30 minutes ago, I told you I'd never been sued.
我希望能继续保持下去
I'd like to keep it that way.
八小时屹立不倒
Instead of showing up here,
还以为他会好好利用一下 没想到跑这儿来了
you'd think he'd put an eight-hour hard-on to good use.
这确实是医疗紧急情况
Well, it is a medical emergency.
如果放任不管 异常勃起可能会导致
If left untreated, priapism can cause
永久性阴茎损伤和终生勃起功能障碍
permanent damage to the penis and erectile dysfunction forever.
感谢你插播的公益广告
Thanks for the PSA.
药剂师配好了去氧肾上腺素 每毫升100微克 共10毫升
Pharmacist mixed up phenylephrine. 10 cc's of 100 mikes per cc.
好极了 这是最大剂量
Great. That's the maximum dose.
单剂量无菌生理盐水
Sterile bolus saline.
你可能需要多备点 因为她们会反复冲洗
You might need to refill since they'll be flushing over and over again.
拿一个空盆 接住他吐出来的任何东西
Hold out the empty basin to catch whatever they pull out.
听明白了吗? 我想是的
Got it? I think so.
如果有需要就喊我
Holler if you need me.
这边情况如何? 他注射了咪达唑仑 已经没意识了
How we doing? Oh, he's out from Versed.
在10点和2点钟方向 给阴茎背神经做了利多卡因阻滞
Did a lidocaine block to the dorsal penile nerves at 10 and 2.
是的 他准备好了 很好
Yeah, he's ready. Excellent.
从背面进针 刺入海绵体
Enter the dorsal side to hit the corpus cavernosum.
我来固定龟头
I'll hold the glans.
扎多深? 两公分
How deep? 2 centimeters.
可以抽了
Now aspirate.
你们每天都干这种事吗?
You guys do this, like, every day?
如果走运的话
If we're lucky.
好了 我们让他平躺 看一下到底是什么东西
Okay, let's lay him down and take a look.
好的
Okay.
会厌视野清晰
Good view of the epiglottis.
谜团解开了
And mystery solved.
这就是早饭吃西兰花的后果
This is what you get for eating broccoli for breakfast.
把它夹出来
Get a good grip on it.
好的
Okay.
我知道为什么海姆立克法没用了
I can see why the Heimlich didn't work.
转一转
Rotate a little bit.
成功!
Voilà!
这就是为何仅用氯胺酮即可
That is why you give ketamine alone,
因为如果用了肌肉松弛药
because if we gave a paralytic,
就必须给他插管 并且上一小时的呼吸机
we would have to intubate and ventilate for an hour.
好了 这位病人要转院至西桥做手术
All right, this guy is going to Westbridge for surgery.
创伤一室很快就空出来了
Trauma 1 will move out shortly.
阿尔茨海默症遗孀艾芙琳·博斯蒂克 可以去观察室看她丈夫了
And our Alzheimer's widow, Evelyn Bostick, can see her husband in the viewing room.
上帝保佑她
God bless her.
迈克尔·威廉的CT结果出来了吗?
My CT results back on Michael Williams?
还没 凯莉的化验结果也没有
Not yet. Neither are the labs on our little girl, Kylie.
那不是我的病人
That's not me.
不过被遗弃的无名氏宝宝 倒是出了一些结果
I did, however, get a few things back on our abandoned baby Jane Doe.
这也不是我的病人
Still not me.
给我吧
I'll take those.
一有消息我们会通知你
Just keeping you informed.
好的
Yep.
好吧
Okay.
我们只是想把她转移到楼上
We're just trying to get her upstairs.
好吧 知道了
Okay. All right, got it.
超级宝宝的尿检结果出来了 白细胞阴性
Superbaby's urine dipped negative 0 WBCs.
呼吸道病原体检测显示鼻病毒阳性
Respiratory panel is positive for rhinovirus,
说明是良性诱因 降钙素原和C反应蛋白结果还没出来
giving us a benign source. Procalcitonin and CRP are pending.
儿科说他们需要先做尿液毒物筛查
Now Pedes is saying they want a urine tox screen
和HIV抗原检测 才愿意接收她
and an HIV antigen before they'll take her.
有点多余了吧
That sounds excessive.
我感觉他们只是想把她留在急诊
I feel like they're just trying to keep her down here.
这能怪他们吗?
Can you blame them?
我就没见过正常的儿科护士
Never met a Pedes nurse yet that wasn't a little wacky.
你知道连续12小时听婴儿哭 会对一个人造成多大精神伤害吗?
You know what 12 hours of crying babies does to a person's psyche?
我差点去了儿科 万幸你没有 相信我
I almost went into Pedes. Good thing you didn't, trust me.
在那儿待久了 你都能得失心疯
Too long up there, you're cuckoo for Cocoa Puffs.
你今天很犀利啊
You are very punchy today.
犀利是我的新基线
Punchy's my new baseline.
谁敢不怀好意地看我 我就把他揍趴下
Anyone even looks at me funny, I'm taking them out,
直插双眼
going right for the eyes.
我会戳瞎你眼睛
I'll eye-gouge you.
你肯定不知道我有这一面吧 不知道
Bet you never knew that about me. I did not.
阿尔-哈希米医生哪去了?
Where is Dr. Al-Hashimi?
去北区5号看异常勃起的患者了 她比我合适
In North 5 with the priapism. Better her than me.
我没有任何性暗示的意思
I did not intend for that to come off as sexual in any way.
好了 我要去看看路易
And on that note, I'm gonna go check on Louie,
然后去救护车停靠区透透气
and then I'm gonna get some air in the ambulance bay.
所以有人需要我 去那儿找我
So, if anybody needs me, that's where I'll be.
明白 船长
Got it, Cap.
看起来侧切牙根部有脓肿
It looks like some pus at the base of the lateral incisor.
我们可以切开 把脓引出来
We can drain that for you.
感觉挺疼的 不会 我们给你上麻药
Sounds like it's gonna hurt. No, we'll numb you up.
要用好麻药
Make sure you use the good stuff.
我会给你用最好的 路易 我保证
It'll be top shelf, Louie, I promise.
这边怎么样?
How we doing in here? Good.
挺好的 快引出来四升了
Almost 4 liters out.
我已经感觉好多了
I already feel like a million bucks.
我只是需要换个机油
I just needed an oil change.
我马上就要切开引流一个根尖脓肿了
And I'm just about to drain an apical abscess.
这就对了嘛
That's what I'm talking about.
我感觉像在做水疗
I feel like I'm having a spa day.
继续加油 维塔克
Keep it up, Whitaker.
这要多久?
How long does this take?
一小时 有时要两小时
Up to an hour, sometimes two.
梅尔 有什么建议吗?
Mel, any suggestions?
评估你的疼痛等级
梅尔 你在退伍军人医疗中心 做过这些
Mel, you did these at the VA.
我们要如何让勃起消退?
How can we facilitate detumescence?
有时按摩阴茎体可能会有帮助
Oh, sometimes massaging the shaft can help.
这都什么虎狼之词啊
Oh, that's what she said.
你可以通过按摩或挤压来清除血栓
You can break up the clots with massage or compression.
懂了
Got it.
你还好吗 梅尔?
You okay, Mel?
她在担心她的庭外质询
She's thinking about her deposition.
只要坚持陈述事实 一切都会迎刃而解的
Just stick with the facts of the case, and it always goes well.
你不是说你没被起诉过吗?
I thought you said you hadn't been sued.
我是没有 但我的很多同事有过
I haven't, but I know many colleagues who have.
我对你的工作也有所了解 金医生
I also know your work, Dr. King.
你病历中的医疗决策部分 一直都记录得十分详尽
Your medical decision-making in the chart is always extremely thorough.
总算是看到希望了
Now we're getting somewhere.
出现疲软的迹象了
First signs of flaccidity.
我真不知道该怎么感谢你
I don't know how I could ever thank you.
我想你已经感谢过了
Well, I think you just did.
你救了我的命
You saved my life.
我什么都没做
I didn't do anything.
这就是你老婆开始像纳粹一样 管控你饮食的下场
This is what happens when your wife starts being a Nazi about your diet.
她居然让我写进食日记
She's got me keeping a food journal.
这是计算卡路里的好办法
It's a good way to count calories.
什么卡路里?
What calories?
她坚持让我每天吃五份蔬菜
She insists I eat five servings of vegetables a day.
兔子都吃不了那么多
A rabbit don't even eat that many vegetables.
我吃猪柳蛋麦满分可从来没噎着过
I ain't never choked on a Sausage Egg McMuffin.
我感觉在这儿待了一整天了
I feel like I've been here all day.
其实你只待了几小时 博斯蒂克太太
It's actually only been a couple of hours, Mrs. Bostick.
我们现在去哪?
Well, where are we going now?
我觉得你可能会想去看看你丈夫
I thought you might like to see your husband.
伊森还在这儿吗?
Is Ethan still here?
是的
Yeah.
好啊
Yes, yes, please.
真是漫长的一天
This has been such a long day.
我很高兴你终于能休息一会了
I'm so glad to see you resting,
但我想时间差不多了 我们该回家了
but I think it's time. We should be going home.
我们回去时可以顺路去一趟商店
If we stop at the store on the way,
我可以去买你做牧羊人派的食材
I can pick up what I need to make your shepherd's pie.
但如果天气很热就算了
But not if it's hot out.
你知道我讨厌在大热天用烤箱
You know how I hate using the oven in the heat.
我们准备好离开了
We're ready to leave now.
罗比医生 现在方便吗?
Dr. Robby, is this a good time?
这要看你想说什么了 阿尔-哈希米医生
That depends on what you have in mind, Dr. Al-Hashimi.
我希望你能看一下 我对改善科室的建议
I'd hoped you would have viewed my ideas for improving the department.
我期待能得到你的反馈
I was looking forward to getting some feedback from you.
好吧 我觉得这个科室运行地很好
Okay, well, I think the department
从各方面来看都是
functions pretty well, all things considered.
我是说 我们和大多数急诊 面临着同样的挑战
I mean, we face the same challenges that most emergency departments face.
我们以生成式人工智能为例
Let's take generative AI, for instance.
急诊科医生花费40%的时间写病历
ER doctors spend 40% of their time charting,
只有28%的时间在患者床旁
only 28% of their time at the bedside.
这个数据不准确吧
That doesn't sound accurate.
我在方案里附上了我的研究 是啊
I've included the study in my packet. Right.
而患者护照已被证明能提升满意度
And patient passports have been shown to increase satisfaction
因为上面会显示每个阶段...
because they show the time required
是的 我这儿有 ...需要等待的时间
for each phase of the visit. Yeah, I got it right here.
什么情况? 一个有攻击性的大学生
What do you got? Combative college kid.
在图书馆突然失控 被校园保安用电击枪击中了脖子
Flipped out in the library, Tased in the neck by campus security.
五支咪达唑仑都没能放倒他
5 midazolam didn't touch him.
你能他妈的别碰我吗?
Will you get the fuck off me?
2901 混蛋!走开!
2901! 2901, motherfucker! Get off!
去你妈的!
Fuck you, man!
你还要继续聊聊你的方案吗?
Want to tell me some more about your ideas?
晚点再说吧 放我出去!
Maybe later. Let me out!
他妈的放我出去!
Let me the fuck out!
放我出去!
Let me out! Let me out!
翻译:肖雪